[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a16", "question": "What was the name of the guy Sam has a crush on in the movie \"Sixteen Candles\"?", "answer": "Jake Ryan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f4684af848b908361b876", "question": "As of 2020, what is the highest grossing film of all time without taking inflation into account?", "answer": "Avengers: Endgame", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59da1b6af6756c9b30ba14f9", "question": "Which roles does Jamie Lee Curtis play in the film \"Halloween H20: 20 Years Later\"?", "answer": "Keri Tate\u00a0and Laurie Strode", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339022", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the hunter who was torn apart by Artemis' dogs?", "answer": "Actaeon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8c", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"The Innocents\" based on?", "answer": "The Turn of the Screw", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c996877e98cb977789f7", "question": "Which city is known as the Glass Capital of the World?", "answer": "Toledo, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdabc2c0b8cce1e6fda705c", "question": "A pentagram's four lower points symbolize air, fire, water and which other item?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12c", "question": "Which Egyptian queen was married to pharaoh Akhenaten?", "answer": "Nefertiti", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339252", "question": "What city is the setting for the movie \"Gladiator\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd84", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Gezora?", "answer": "Cuttlefish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"luau\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f12", "question": "What author created Narnia?", "answer": "C. S. Lewis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae95d6574a5ce6b56b825a", "question": "By what name is Beethoven's sixth symphony known?", "answer": "The Pastoral Symphony", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec840fec223966ae8f87fb", "question": "What was the first TV kids show in the US?", "answer": "Howdy Doody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912b", "question": "Which famed science fiction author wrote the novelization for the 1966 film, \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fcc1a23c97eb73f6a51a26c", "question": "What was Tom Hardy's first feature film?", "answer": "Black Hawk Down", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f3f7caf848b908361b86c", "question": "What do the numbers on a roulette wheel add up to?", "answer": "666", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa3d86ce05a3942286eab", "question": "Whose hand is shown drawing the charcoal portrait of Kate Winslet in \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "James Cameron's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb67", "question": "What is the name of the six-pointed star which is the symbol of Judaism?", "answer": "Star of David", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029f9bcad1ec93f27df762", "question": "What continent does yerba mate originates from?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e90fd7fd7247dfc0fa00307", "question": "Who is the first Prime Minister of Italy, also a leading figure in the Italian unification?", "answer": "Camillo Benso", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0e", "question": "Moroni is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Comoros", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa60", "question": "What two countries share Lake Geneva?", "answer": "France and Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391dd", "question": "Who played Mr. Orange in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Tim Roth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7e7fff048f679a45ac10", "question": "Belonephobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Pins and needles?", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1fa", "question": "Which country were the 1992 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14e", "question": "Arturo Toscanini played what instrument before conducting?", "answer": "The Cello", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ff9513a3a814d89068c53", "question": "What is Ethiopia's official language?", "answer": "Amharic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937ecc208d98002fdd633c0", "question": "Which US state's way of life and culture is described as Cajun?", "answer": "Louisiana's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56b", "question": "What plant has a name from the French meaning \"lion's tooth\"?", "answer": "Dandelion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fd", "question": "Which mint was the first to be used as a gum flavoring by the Wrigley Company?", "answer": "Spearmint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31e", "question": "Constance Markievicz, became the first ever what In 1918?", "answer": "British female MP", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989a", "question": "What dancer from Omaha was born Fred Austerlitz?", "answer": "Fred Astaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d1", "question": "What distance did the Romans once define as a thousand paces?", "answer": "A mile", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3d0254f032c0db195b497", "question": "What was the Year of the Five Emperors?", "answer": "In 193 AD, there were five claimants for the title of Roman Emperor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5be57fc05415ba52ed6f0aae", "question": "What crop is attacked by the Colorado beetle?", "answer": "Potato", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac32", "question": "What is the oldest university in the US?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e3", "question": "What was the middle name of composer Bach?", "answer": "Sebastian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062ba7c9d816e292245c22", "question": "What is the name of Captain Ahab's ship?", "answer": "The Pequod", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6562bae7e414034b5aec2", "question": "Which ancient civilization created zodiac signs?", "answer": "Babylonia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339111", "question": "What boxer appeared in the broadway musical \"Buck White\" in 1969?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008f30cf842fa4c4ba96b9", "question": "Italian painter Jacopo Comin is better known as who?", "answer": "Tintoretto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078b710eee65b76b9f2668", "question": "What name was given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008df6cf4f3bc4a292f862a", "question": "What did Zacchaeus do in order to catch a glimpse at Jesus Christ?", "answer": "Zacchaeus climbed a tree so he could have clear view of the Messiah on his way to Jericho.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03d", "question": "Of what descent is Peter, on the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Irish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998b", "question": "What was the name of the main police detective played by Jack Webb on the TV show \"Dragnet\"?", "answer": "Joe Friday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f61", "question": "Eric Arthur Blair was better known by what pen name?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef0", "question": "In boxing who suffered defeats to Tim Witherspoon, Mike Tyson and Lennox Lewis?", "answer": "Frank Bruno", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062be2c9d816e292245c26", "question": "Which Henri Matisse painting was hung upside down at the Museum of Modern Art in New York for 46 days without anyone noticing?", "answer": "Le Bateau (\"The Boat\"), a paper-cut, caused a stir in 1961 when the Museum of Modern Art in New York hung the work upside-down.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9386a6bd93ce3a4e5f684", "question": "What cosmologist theorized the creation of the universe from quantum fluctuations?", "answer": "Alexander Vilenkin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c3e97a9ebfabb9c85d8a965", "question": "Which popular beverage's name is German for \"storeroom\"?", "answer": "Lager", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a6", "question": "Winesap, Cortland, McIntosh and Rome are all types of what?", "answer": "Apples", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3d", "question": "What slogan did Nancy Reagan create for her drug awareness campaign?", "answer": "Just Say No", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f80301dd7bf43be5e83c", "question": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40b", "question": "In what country was margarine first patented?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338966", "question": "What is the English title of the Manet painting depicting a nude woman enjoying a picnic with two clothed men?", "answer": "The Luncheon on the Grass", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f9", "question": "What was the name of cat who could drive a car on \"Saturday Night Live\"?", "answer": "Toonces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda4", "question": "What group's honor society is the Order of the Arrow?", "answer": "The Boy Scouts of America", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae3", "question": "Bob Eubanks was the original host of what game show where couples competed against each other?", "answer": "The Newlywed Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c39", "question": "What book won Harper Lee a Pulitzer Prize in 1961?", "answer": "To Kill A Mockingbird", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb5b6e5dad637d903c881a", "question": "What luxury fashion house funded the restoration of Rome's Trevi Fountain?", "answer": "Fendi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc9176de0eb824d405301", "question": "Where is the New York City Marathon start line?", "answer": "Staten Island -- It starts at the base of the Verrazano-Narrows Bridge in Staten Island and ends in Central Park.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58bb33cde368446ca7bd6848", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", what is the name of the shrew?", "answer": "Katherina", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a740", "question": "Albuquerque is located on the shores of what river?", "answer": "Rio Grande River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b2", "question": "What town is Oklahoma State University located in?", "answer": "Stillwater", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062a94c9d816e292245c1a", "question": "Coosje van Bruggen and Claes Oldenburg first collaborated on what sculpture?", "answer": "The husband/wife team, first collaborated on\u00a0\"Flashlight\"\u00a0(1981), a huge outdoor sculpture at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b659", "question": "Apple Brown Betty is a dessert comprised of apples and what?", "answer": "Brown sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e9", "question": "On what TV series did Katie Holmes first achieve stardom from 1998 to 2003?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf5", "question": "The candy PEZ was first sold in which country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add9", "question": "What year was napalm first used?", "answer": "1944", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff3", "question": "What movie star founded the Hole in the Wall summer camps for ill children?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a616", "question": "Where is the Trafalgar Cemetery located?", "answer": "Gibraltar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81f", "question": "What is the Japanese word for \"harbor wave\"?", "answer": "Tsunami", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945f", "question": "How does Jack die in the movie \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "He freezes to death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc1d7ec223966ae8f886e", "question": "The \"Tina\" in Tina Fey is short for what name?", "answer": "Stamatina", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c012", "question": "What did a Cordwainer make?", "answer": "Shoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b2", "question": "Who was responsible for \"conducting\" the underground railroad rescuing slaves during the US Civil War?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910a", "question": "What year was Viktor Frankl's book \"Man's Search for Meaning\" published?", "answer": "1946", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded30aea2747c8aff16d44", "question": "Which band took their name from a type of light motor truck manufactured primarily before World War II?", "answer": "REO Speedwagon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f85", "question": "In the nursery rhyme what is Friday's child?", "answer": "Loving and Giving", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe93b546bd93ce3a4e5f6a2", "question": "What is the study of water called?", "answer": "Hydrology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddaa36ce05a3942286d88", "question": "Where in Mexico does Andy say he dreams of living in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Andy confides in Red that his dream place to live in is Zihuatanejo.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43f", "question": "What mammal's most common species is the bottlenose?", "answer": "Dolphin's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f16", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Robert Downey and Eddie Izzard?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cdc8bb53d1af658864ec", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "1939", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7a", "question": "What war is the setting for the novel \"All Quiet on the Western Front\"?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389fb", "question": "Whose paintings include \"Two Half-Naked Women Seen from Behind in the Rue des Moulins Brothel\"?", "answer": "Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ed3a06d333868d34d76b", "question": "The first TV commercial for a toy aired in 1952 featuring what toy?", "answer": "Mr. Potato Head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c203877e98cb97778983", "question": "Who named the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c7", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering energy quanta?", "answer": "Max Planck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b63c", "question": "What liquid did Swiss candle maker Daniel Peter first add to chocolate in 1867?", "answer": "Milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace2", "question": "What was New York's Liberty Island called before its name was changed in 1956?", "answer": "Bedloe's Island", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a98", "question": "What early rock and roll pioneer's real first and middle name was Charles Hardin?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a022", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who is Stewie's half-brother and nemesis?", "answer": "Bertram", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d12", "question": "Whose last novel was 1961's \"The Winter of Our Discontent\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29c", "question": "Who sang the theme song of the Bond film \"For Your Eyes Only\"?", "answer": "Sheena Easton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e0", "question": "What fashion designer owns Maxim's restaurant in Paris?", "answer": "Pierre Cardin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d57", "question": "Whose mysterious murder ends the film \"Gorillas in the Mist\"?", "answer": "Dian Fossey's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd73ae347d002c297e4c0", "question": "Which is the rainiest US state?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc3536ce05a3942286f22", "question": "What is the name of Jack Nicholson's character in the film, \"Chinatown\"?", "answer": "J.J \"Jake\" Gittes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d9", "question": "Which artist recorded the 1982 hit song \"Bad to the Bone\"?", "answer": "George Thorogood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88c", "question": "The seismic belt called the Ring of Fire surrounds what body of water?", "answer": "The Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339137", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Apollo?", "answer": "Apollo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b854", "question": "What team won the first Super Bowl?", "answer": "The Green Bay Packers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9c", "question": "Sophophobia is known as the phobia of what?", "answer": "Learning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a035", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", who relays the Black-U-Weather forecast?", "answer": "Ollie Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a53", "question": "In the Golden Earring song \"Radar Love\", what country artist do they hear playing on the radio?", "answer": "Brenda Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e72cbaad0874f1a5e2d1c21", "question": "How many years is a \"Copyright Protection\" granted in the United States to an author after their death?", "answer": "70 years", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b029", "question": "What California coastal town hosted the first major rock festival in 1967?", "answer": "Monterey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d47", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Empire Records\"?", "answer": "Robin Tunney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a59e", "question": "In what mountains is Camp David?", "answer": "Appalachian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac27", "question": "The Panama Canal connects the Gulf of Panama and which sea?", "answer": "Caribbean sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a120", "question": "Which year did John Schlesinger receive an Academy Award for directing \"Midnight Cowboy\"?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fb", "question": "What type of cloud can form a tornado?", "answer": "Cumulonimbus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b628", "question": "\"St. Vitus's Dance\" is what?", "answer": "A type of brain disorder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6007822ebd51d85e222ab654", "question": "What title was Henri Matisse's \"Harmony in Red\" originally commissioned under?", "answer": "The painting was originally commissioned in blue. Matisse was dissatisfied with the result and repainted the entire painting red.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca22", "question": "What is the shadow-casting pointer on a sundial called?", "answer": "Gnomon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b7ffb133a3a814d89068c61", "question": "The US made \"Medium Tank, M4\" is better known as what?", "answer": "The Sherman tank", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe52d2c1bf59ab7d2e3810c", "question": "What is a grouping of bananas called?", "answer": "A hand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c842", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the medulla?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339013", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Northanger Abbey\"?", "answer": "Jane Austen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b3", "question": "The term Sesquincentennial represents how many years ?", "answer": "150", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597ddf6d77980686f722d185", "question": "What city was host to the first official Association football game in 1863?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338909", "question": "Who wrote \"The Hunchback of Notre Dame\"?", "answer": "Victor Hugo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5901d794709c1c34536e6ea3", "question": "What was the first flavor of the malt beverage named \"Zima\"?", "answer": "Lemon-Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fd", "question": "What do scientists call the \u201cbelt\u201d that is orbiting the sun between Mars and Jupiter?", "answer": "Asteroid Belt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a02", "question": "What 1980\u2019s game show often featured contestants asking for \"no Whammys!\"?", "answer": "Press Your Luck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c055", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iran?", "answer": "Common nightingale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b3ba06d333868d34d6dc", "question": "In what year did the Korean War end?", "answer": "Although hostilities ended in 1953, there was never a formal peace treaty as of 2020", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f4d68af848b908361b881", "question": "What was the number of Twitter\u2019s original character limit?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c8610775fa611bce67de", "question": "What instrument's name literally translates as \"jumping flea\"?", "answer": "Ukulele -- Meaning \"jumping flea\" in Hawaiian, the ukulele is about as closely linked to the island state as leis and the hula.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab88", "question": "Phnom Penh is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d4", "question": "What is Billie Holiday's birth name?", "answer": "Eleanora Fagan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338957", "question": "What is by far the most famous painting in the Louvre?", "answer": "The Mona Lisa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ac", "question": "When did author J. D. Salinger die?", "answer": "2010", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60173fdc44491cbd7c5a17b7", "question": "John the Baptist's father was who?", "answer": "The father of John the Baptist was Zechariah.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70deaf96e155acab35d36", "question": "What two boxers fought in the famous match-up dubbed the \"Thrilla in Manila\"?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali and Joe Frazier", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c349c815febcc896f9253", "question": "On which of the Canary Island would you find the holiday destination of Corralejo?", "answer": "Fuerteventura", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339213", "question": "What is the make of the car used as a time machine in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "DeLorean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5d", "question": "What literary work inspired Sting's \"Moon Over Bourbon Street\" song?", "answer": "Interview with a Vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c098", "question": "How many rings are there on the Olympic flag?", "answer": "Five", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e0", "question": "What creature has the world's largest eyes?", "answer": "Colossal Squid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab13cbbaab681b0929216e", "question": "In the automotive world, what does the abbreviation CVT stand for?", "answer": "Continuously Variable Transmission", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87a", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"La Rambla\"?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffe4c5047818f5674af01b6", "question": "How did Robert Frost sum up everything he learned about life?", "answer": "\"It goes on.\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbfda6ce05a3942286f06", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Tango in the Night\"?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbd", "question": "What model was married to musician Travis Barker?", "answer": "Shanna Moakler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea462cff048f679a45ab9f", "question": "Which fruit is also known as \"courgette\"?", "answer": "Zucchini", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339462", "question": "Who is Sulley's sidekick in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Mike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63f", "question": "What is the top speed a freefalling object can reach called?", "answer": "Terminal Velocity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bc", "question": "What are the three main types of sugar?", "answer": "Glucose, fructose and sucrose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b837", "question": "What color is always at the top of a single rainbow?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e9a2cebfabb9c85d8a978", "question": "Which British Prime Minister died in 1965?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd69f806c0f9723ab15cb2b", "question": "Who was the final Emperor of India?", "answer": "George VI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8a", "question": "In Greek mythology, for who did the cyclops forge thunderbolts?", "answer": "Zeus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abea", "question": "Easter Island is a part of which South American country?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c919", "question": "What type of number has no factors other than 1 and itself?", "answer": "Prime", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a501", "question": "Which side of Niagara Falls has the largest falls - the US or Canadian side?", "answer": "Canadian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937ea0608d98002fdd6339e", "question": "Which Stephen King novel is set at the \"Overlook Hotel\"?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab99c6121a8909e5c332d35", "question": "Which band released the album \"Breakfast in America\"?", "answer": "Supertramp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8c", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is James Smith?", "answer": "LL Cool J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26f", "question": "In 1991, who erected three thousand blue and yellow umbrellas on the coasts of California and Japan?", "answer": "Christo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd9692c23c87fd04dd15e07", "question": "Who is credited as designing the first gas-powered car?", "answer": "Karl Benz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b934", "question": "What color is the 3 ball in pool?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae18", "question": "Which river did Washington cross on Christmas night 1776?", "answer": "Delaware River", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe523531bf59ab7d2e380ef", "question": "Swarovski is associated with what product?", "answer": "Chrystal jewelry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1f378145fb2946670739a", "question": "What cheese is traditionally used on a Reuben sandwich?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339195", "question": "What was the first CD ever pressed in the US?", "answer": "Bruce Springsteen's Born in the USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ab1201dd7bf43be5e763", "question": "What is a credenza?", "answer": "A dining sideboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f0", "question": "What is the fear of heredity known as?", "answer": "Patroiophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c89d5b011619dd6d415485", "question": "In what season of South Park did the boys claim that Butters wrote the book \"Scrotie McBoogerballs\"?", "answer": "Season 14", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c7", "question": "The resort city of Aspen is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b67801dd7bf43be5e7dd", "question": "What city drops a giant Peeps chick for the New Year every year?", "answer": "Bethlehem, Pennsylvania", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe767d3eec85e375820b297", "question": "Which Canadian province produces the most maple syrup?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a748", "question": "What island in California was once called Pelican Island?", "answer": "Alcatraz Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e9a606d333868d34d757", "question": "During World War II, the U.S. purchase more than 150 million pounds of what to feed its troops?", "answer": "SPAM", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85d", "question": "What winds bring warm, dry, smog-free weather to southern California every autumn?", "answer": "The Santa Ana winds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339731", "question": "Audrey Hepburn was born in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e32cfe83fe1f2a824ba8", "question": "What was the significance of Guadalcanal to Japan?", "answer": "The island was in an ideal position for controlling the Solomon Islands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b23aed98f1a2238a7cb2b3e", "question": "What two countries noticed that they had the same flag at the 1936 Olympics in Berlin?", "answer": "Haiti and Liechtenstein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6aa", "question": "What cave, found in central Kentucky, is the world's longest cave system?", "answer": "Mammoth Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa566cc73aa70ea0b70b2b", "question": "Which country hosts the World Ice Golf Championship?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c651", "question": "How many daily tides are there?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339803", "question": "What movie did rappers Ice Cube & Ice T star in?", "answer": "Tresspass", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed4", "question": "How many camels carried the 117,000 volumes of Abdul Kassem Ismael's library?", "answer": "400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa55bbc73aa70ea0b70b26", "question": "In which Asian city is the historic waterfront called The Bund?", "answer": "Shanghai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b3ade662d71a53650fe1", "question": "What unique quirk did Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Chopin have?", "answer": "He preferred to play in the dark.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6f", "question": "What was the name of Rhett and Scarlett\u2019s daughter in \"Gone With the Wind\"?", "answer": "Bonnie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f5", "question": "What century did curling originate in Scotland?", "answer": "16th Century", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cf0c94b094db915830ac", "question": "In which country would you find the Aya Castle?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2f", "question": "What country was the birthplace of two of the Three Tenors?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e4", "question": "In the movie \"Toy Story\" what is the name of the boy next door who blows up toys?", "answer": "Sid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddffd6ce05a3942286db5", "question": "Which American sitcom once aired an episode entitled \"April Fool's Day\" which was actually about Tax Day?", "answer": "\"Roseanne\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999f", "question": "In \"Back to the Future\", when Marty goes back in time, what does his mother think his first name is?", "answer": "Calvin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a8ee90aac110e4167093", "question": "What French beverage is made by mixing apple juice with apple brandy and aging it in barrels?", "answer": "Pommeau", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c77d3d824f0f7a362efd554", "question": "Who was the last man from the Apollo program to have walked on the Moon?", "answer": "Eugene Cernan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ce", "question": "Which Mario Kart game first featured 12 racers instead of 8?", "answer": "Mario Kart Wii", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015eaaafe83fe1f2a824bf2", "question": "Who claimed he could \"drive away the devil with a fart\"?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87f", "question": "In what US city would you find the fashionable Dupont Circle neighborhood?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c604", "question": "Which planet is named after the God of Love?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c7", "question": "What musical character came from the easterly wind with an umbrella and carpet bag?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3e7144f0f6af5b06664c", "question": "What did David Stirling form in 1941?", "answer": "SAS (Special Air Service)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4a7649076251badbeab6", "question": "Who patented the concept of a flat engine in 1896?", "answer": "Karl Benz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abfd", "question": "The Mus\u00e9e d'Orsay in Paris was originally what?", "answer": "Railway Station", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cc", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Stormin' Norman\"?", "answer": "Norman Schwarzkopf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9dd70e748bb36357acde1", "question": "In the movie \"National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation\", what does Aunt Bethany recite when asked to say grace?", "answer": "The Pledge of Allegiance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abff", "question": "In which US state would you find Devils Tower?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5d", "question": "Which flower is also known as the \"Lent Lily\"?\u00a0", "answer": "The daffodil", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b372", "question": "What was the name of the scandal that forced President Nixon to resign?", "answer": "Watergate\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca99", "question": "The Larynx is also called what?", "answer": "Voice box", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bcf", "question": "In Norse mythology who are the female attendants of Odin?", "answer": "The Valkyrie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600b86961d8c1817608d53e6", "question": "What kind of person shall not be honored on a US postal stamp, according to the USPS and the Citizen\u2019s Stamp Advisory Committee?", "answer": "A living person", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f5c501dd7bf43be5e82b", "question": "What variety of bananas is the most commonly sold in stores?", "answer": "Cavendish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a162c85f01ec323f8491730", "question": "The song \"Matchmaker, Matchmaker\" came from which musical?", "answer": "Fiddler on the Roof", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b505", "question": "What two skills make up the winter biathlon?", "answer": "Cross-country skiing and target shooting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c567", "question": "What name is given to the device which consists of a frame with parallel wires carrying beads used for computation?", "answer": "Abacus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe939bf6bd93ce3a4e5f690", "question": "What term describes the hazy-looking patch surrounding the nucleus of a comet?", "answer": "Coma", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a3", "question": "What three-letter word means the smallest piece of information used by a computer?", "answer": "Bit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b16f", "question": "What architect was responsible for the design of the Brooklyn Bridge?", "answer": "John Augustus Roebling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8ab4d01dd7bf43be5e767", "question": "What part of the computer does \"QWERTY\" refer to?", "answer": "The keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3589855db0d66a186cb54c", "question": "The Republic of Benin shares a border with which other African country to the east?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa6", "question": "What is the easternmost state in the contiguous US?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c678", "question": "In which US state can one find Kodiak Bears?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef93af6ce05a3942286e91", "question": "Andy Dufresne was particularly skilled and knowledgeable in what in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Finance and Taxation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e65506d333868d34d731", "question": "What food did the Christian church ban during lent that help leads to its popularity on Easter?", "answer": "Eggs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7abce66490a8cc1a6e529c", "question": "In The Maze Runner, what does \"WICKED\" stand for?", "answer": "World In Catastrophe: Killzone Experiment Department", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb2a42c9bff04efae6d75e", "question": "What was writer Eric Arthur Blair's pen name?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b3", "question": "What pop star's fans are famed for wearing grass skirts and doing the \"fin dance\" at shows?", "answer": "Jimmy Buffet's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd42", "question": "What hall of Famer played his entire major-league career for the Minnesota Twins?", "answer": "Kirby Puckett", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c359", "question": "On which planet did the spacecraft Venus 8 land in 1972?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a3", "question": "What agricultural crop is Cuba's main export?", "answer": "Sugar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7b", "question": "Harare is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Zimbabwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339520", "question": "What does Mahoney teach Hightower to do in the movie \"Policy Academy\"?", "answer": "Drive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2eda58d116dab4aecb43", "question": "Who played Wayne Szalinski's wife in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Marcia Strassman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358e1d5db0d66a186cb566", "question": "During the 1990\u2019s who recorded the albums \"Out of Time\" and \"New Adventures in Hi-Fi\"?", "answer": "R.E.M.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993d", "question": "Who played the role of Bud Bundy on the TV show \"Married with Children\"?", "answer": "David Faustino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf40", "question": "Who patented the safety razor in 1895?", "answer": "King Gillette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e932a7ccba3ffe45786c2", "question": "What painting technique uses colored pigments mixed with a binder, most common of which are egg yolks?", "answer": "Tempera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab1b1ec4fda37788a9a1db4", "question": "Which once-common disease was also known as the \"Great white plague\"?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff5125fff04d658268c92cf", "question": "What group of American women displayed their loyalty following the passage of the Townshend Acts in 1767?", "answer": "The\u00a0Daughters of Liberty\u00a0used their traditional skills to develope substitutes for goods sold by the British.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b542", "question": "What was the official language of England for over 600 years?", "answer": "French", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da6", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Superman II\"?", "answer": "E. G. Marshall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a751", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Hawkeye State\"?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339954", "question": "What Grammy-\u00adwinning 1990\u2019s band was fronted by Darius Rucker?", "answer": "Hootie & the Blowfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002437a4be4723ccac22197", "question": "Which 1996 novel by Nicholas Sparks begins with an old man called Noah Calhoun reading to a woman in a nursing home?", "answer": "\"The Notebook\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd89", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Megalon?", "answer": "Beetle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad84", "question": "Who was the first Russian Czar to westernize Russia?", "answer": "Peter I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be98", "question": "What does \"PT\" stand for in the names of Navy PT boats?", "answer": "Patrol Torpedo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339997", "question": "What TV sidekick was portrayed by Jay Silverheels?", "answer": "Tonto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa6", "question": "What animated trio is made up of Master Shake, Frylock, and Meatwad?", "answer": "Aqua Teen Hunger Force", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e5f11e3d274615ecf51453c", "question": "\"Oscitation\", is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Yawning", "category": "science"}]